Guide to the Syria Collection of photographs AD.MC.036
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Syria Collection
1940s-1980s
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Nikolskaya, Xenia
Unknown
A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beirut, [Lebanon]
Above Cinema Mounir, Syria
Al Douli International Studio, Damascus (Syria)
Ali Baba, Syria
Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]
Apamis, Aleppo, Syria
C. Almas [?], Damascus, [Syria]
Cairo Studio, Ahmed Hariri, Damascus, [Syria]
Hassen Yazil, Syria
Issa Freres, Beyrouth (Beirut, Lebanon)
Photo Boyadjian, 65 Avenue Barada, Damascus, Syria
Photo Cine Azad, Damascus, [Syria]
Photo J. Gazarian, Bab Touma, Damascus, Syria
Photo Katchadour, Damascus, [Syria]
Photo Kermanik, Syria
Photo Rapide, Grand Hotel Bloudan, Semerjdian Frères, [Syria]
Photo V. Derounian, Aleppo, Syria
Qusai, Aleppo, Syria
Rahe, Syria
Reem Color, Damascus, Syria
Sadek Qassees, Damascus, Syria
Samir Color Lab, Saudi Arabia
Sarkissian Studio, Damascus, Syria
Sons et Couleurs (Beirut, Lebanon)
Studio Abdel Nour, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Al Ahram, Aleppo, [Syria]
Studio Al Andalous, Syria
Studio Al Assime, [Syria]
Studio Al Khayyam, Damascus, Syria
Studio Al Sabah, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Al-Babk, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Al-Kindi, Syria
Studio Al-Rabih, [Syria]
Studio Alsabah, Damascus, Syria
Studio Antoin, Damascus, Syria
Studio Carmen, Damascus, Syria
Studio Dikran, Damascus, Syria
Studio Dunia, Derhagopian, Rue Fouad, 1er, Damas (Syria)
Studio Echbelia, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Egypt, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Garbis, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Georges Derzi, Press Photography Department, Salhieh, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Hadad, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Haig, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Housam, Syria
Studio Hovnan, Damascus, Syria
Studio Karwan, [Syria]
Studio Khallaf, Syria
Studio Le Caire, Damascus, Syria
Studio Manuel, Syria
Studio Minas, Chouhada, Salhiyeh, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Mismar, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Monsour, Damascus, Syria
Studio Najah, Damascus, Syria
Studio Najah, [Syria]
Studio Omayad, Rue Fardosse, Damas (Damascus, Syria)
Studio Rateb, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Safar & Vartan, Fardosse Street, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Safar, Sanjakdar, Damas (Syria)
Studio Sameer, Damascus, Syria
Studio Suri Ramis, Syria
Studio Tuni and Safar, Damascus, Syria
Studio Venge, [Syria]
Studio Vense, Syria
Studio Wacim, Abou Roumaneh, Miseloun Street, Damascus, [Syria]
Studio Yazouy, Damascus, Syria
Studio Zaven, Syria
Studio Zenobia, [Syria]
Studio el Seyahe, Damascus, Syria
Tirage Photo Dadour, Alep (Syria)
Triage Photo Dadour, Aleppo, [Syria]
Yacoub Touranian, Jordan
AD.MC.036
9 paige_boxes 1,255 photographs and 25 negatives in 8 boxes and 1 oversized flat box.
.
Box 1 - 9
Arrangement
Organized into ten series according to the order in which the materials were received from the donor.
The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Marie Rose Krikorian Series - Box: 5; Box: 9 Adel Bassem Series Studio Portraits Amphitheater Series - Box: 4 Actor Headshots Series Series - Box: 5 Party Series Series - Box: 5 Aleppo Series Series - Box: 6 Studio Series II Series - Box: 7 Studio Series III Series - Box: 8 Wedding Portrait Series
Scope and Contents
Acquired from photographer Xenia Nikolskaya, the Syria Collection includes 1,255 photographs including black and white gelatin silver prints and color photographs, as well as 25 negatives. The images document the social and cultural life of Syria from the 1940's to the 1980's. They portray religious ceremonies, daily life, street scenes of Damascus, archaeological sites, schools, picnics, family trips, costume parties, historic sites, and landscapes. There are also 10 photographs taken in Lebanon.
Biographical / Historical
.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All images acquired from Xenia Nikolskaya in 2018.
Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Sports; Nikolskaya, Xenia
- Marie Rose Krikorian Series (Box 5, Box 9, Box 1)
  - An individual portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian in front of a door., Circa 1940-1960; 12092; Unknown; 9 x 13.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Hats; Individual Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with a woman., Circa 1940-1960; 12093; Unknown; 13.4 x 8.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photographic Prints; Syria; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - An individual portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian. (link ref1, 4)., 1940-1960; 12094; Unknown; 9 x 13.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits
  - An individual portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian (link ref 1, 3)., Circa 1940-1960; 12095; Unknown; 9 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photographic Prints; Hats; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Syria
  - A studio portrait of a Marie Rose Krikorian wearing a head cover., Circa 1940-1960; 12096; Unknown; 18 x 11.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Studio Photography; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A studio portrait of Jareh Krikorian wearing a striped tie., Circa 1940-1960; 12097; Studio Dikran, Damascus, Syria; 17.5 x 11.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Damascus, Syria; Men; Signatures; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A studio portrait of Jareh Krikorian wearing a striped tie (linked ref6)., Circa 1940-1960; 12098; Studio Dikran, Damascus, Syria; 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Damascus, Syria; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Signatures; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men
  - A portrait of a woman sitting next to a "PFAFF" sewing machine. (link ref9, 10)., Circa 1950-1965; 12099; Unknown; 13 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Furnishings; Sewing; Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A portrait of a woman standing in front of a large sewing machine. (link ref8, 10)., Circa 1950-1965; 12100; Unknown; 13.1 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Sewing; Women; Individual Portraits; Syria; Photographic Prints
  - A woman operating a sewing machine, next Marie Rose Krikorian who is wearing a headscarf. (link ref8, 9)., Circa 1950-1965; 12101; Unknown; 13 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Sewing; Group Portraits; Women
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian and a man seated at a table on a terrace., Circa 1940-1960; 12102; A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beirut, [Lebanon]; 11.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Fezes/Tarbouches; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Beirut, Lebanon; Drinks/Beverages; Fur Garments; Gloves; Restaurants/bars; Outdoors
  - Marie Rose Krikorian seated at a table with two men., Circa 1955-1970; 12103; Unknown; 12.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Furnishings; Smoking; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Drinks/Beverages; Cigarettes; Restaurants/bars
  - A side profile of Marie Rose Krikorian and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1955-1970; 12104; Unknown; 12.7 x 17.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Men; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A side profile of Marie Rose Krikorian wearing sunglasses in a vehicle., Circa 1950-1970; 12105; Unknown; 11 x 17.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Syria; Individual Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A side profile of a woman., Circa 1950-1970; 12106; Unknown; 13.1 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Syria; Individual Portraits
  - An individual portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian., Circa 1950-1970; 12107; Unknown; 17.9 x 13.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Marie Rose Krikorian standing behind a child seated on a chair., Circa 1940-1960; 12108; Unknown; 9 x 6.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian and a multi-generational group in the middle of a street., Circa 1940-1960; 12109; Unknown; 6.3 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; French Writing; Boys
  - A full-body portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian against a fabric backdrop., Circa 1940-1960; 12110; Unknown; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - An individual portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children., Circa 1940-1960; 12111; Unknown; 6.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Cameras; Individual Portraits; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian and a woman holding a child., Circa 1940-1960; 12112; Unknown; 9 x 6.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Syria; Group Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with a multi-generational group in front of a tent., Circa 1940-1960; 12113; Unknown; 6.2 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Syria; Tents; Children; Men; Group Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - An individual portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children beside a tree., Circa 1940-1960; 12114; Unknown; 8.7 x 6.3 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Syria; French Writing
  - A studio portrait of a man and a woman with a child., Circa 1940-1960; 12115; Studio Dunia, Derhagopian, Rue Fouad, 1er, Damas (Syria); 13.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Children; Damascus, Syria; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group surrounding a table with two cakes., Circa 1940-1960; 12116; Unknown; 6.1 x 8.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Women; Men; Children; Group Portraits; Syria; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Food; Parties; Girls; Boys; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - A studio portrait of a child sitting cross-legged., Circa 1940-1960; 12117; Unknown; 13.7 x 8.4 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Individual Portraits; Syria; Studio Photography; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Marie Rose Krikorian dancing with her husband, Jareh Krikorian (link ref28)., Circa 1955-1970; 12118; Unknown; 17.9 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Dancing; Syria; Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian and Jareh Krikorian (link ref27)., Circa 1955-1970; 12119; Unknown; 17.9 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Group Portraits; Men; Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dancing
  - A group portrait of individuals in two lines shaking hands, including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1955-1970; 12120; 13.1 x 18.3 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Women
  - A multi-generational group gathered in a room including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1945-1965; 12121; Unknown; 13 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Syria; Women; Children; Group Portraits; Men; Gatherings; Parties; Boys; Girls
  - A group of men and women dancing., Circa 1940-1970; 12122; Unknown; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Syria; Dancing; Men; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A woman and man dancing (link ref32)., Circa 1940-1970; 12123; Unknown; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Dancing; Syria; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A group portrait of a crowd., Circa 1950-1970; 12124; Studio Minas, Chouhada, Salhiyeh, Damascus, [Syria]; 13.1 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Damascus, Syria; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - Marie Rose Krikorian seated with a multi-generational group at a table., June 1954; 12125; Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]; 13.2 x 18.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Group Portraits; Furnishings; Lebanon; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Drinks/Beverages; Restaurants/bars; Children
  - A woman and man dancing (link ref32)., Circa 1955-1970; 12126; Unknown; 17.9 x 12.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Marie Rose Krikorian holding a baby to her face while seated., Circa 1940-1960; 12127; Unknown; 6.1 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Syria; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children
  - A group portrait of the baptism of Marie Rose Krikorian's son., Circa 1940-1960; 12128; Unknown; 6.1 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Women; Syria; Baptisms; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Gatherings; Children; Facial Hair; Boys
  - A group portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children's baptism., Circa 1940-1960; 12129; Unknown; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Baptisms; Girls; Women; Syria; Children; Religious Ceremony; Priests/Clergymen; Gatherings; Facial Hair; Events/Occasions; Religious Crosses; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Group Portraits
  - A group portrait of the baptism of Marie Rose Krikorian's child., Circa 1940-1960; 12130; Unknown; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Photographic Prints; Children; Baptisms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Syria; Women; Religious Ceremony; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair; Events/Occasions; Girls; Boys; Christians
  - A priest holding Marie Rose Krikorian's child during a baptism., Circa 1940-1960; 12131; Unknown; 6.2 x 8.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Men; Women; Baptisms; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Syria; Religious Ceremony; Gatherings; Children; Group Portraits; Events/Occasions; Facial Hair; Boys; Girls; Christians
  - A woman sitting by a door and holding a child., Circa 1940-1960; 12132; Unknown; 9 x 6.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Syria; Children; Furnishings; Group Portraits
  - A portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian's child in a flower basinet before baptism., Circa 1940-1960; 12133; Unknown; 8.9 x 6.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Individual Portraits; Baptisms; Syria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Children
  - Marie Rose Krikorian bathing a child in a tub with a woman assisting., Circa 1940-1960; 12134; Unknown; 11.2 x 6.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Syria; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Children
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with two children., Circa 1940-1960; 12135; Unknown; 6.2 x 8.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Children; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Syria; Boys
  - A group portrait of a clergyman baptizing a child standing in a tub. Jareh Krikorian stands off to the side., Circa 1940-1960; 12136; Unknown; 6.3 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Group Portraits; Syria; Children; Baptisms; Priests/Clergymen; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Ceremony; Men; Girls; Books; Women; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Boys; Events/Occasions; Christians
  - A multi-generational group standing in front of five glass panels, including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1940-1960; 12137; Unknown; 8.7 x 13.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Syria; Men; Women; Girls; Boys
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; 12138; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Syria; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Food; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a young child blowing candles on a cake., Circa 1940-1960; 12139; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.6 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Group Portraits; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Food; Men; Women; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 47, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; 12140; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Food; Syria; Furnishings; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Food; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 47, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; 12141; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Children; Food; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food. (duplicate ref55, 54, 47, 50, 49, 52)., Circa 1940-1960; 12142; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Children; Food; Women; Furnishings; Syria; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 54, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; 12143; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Furnishings; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Syria; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Food; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group portrait including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1945-1965; 12144; Unknown; 8.8 x 13.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Children; Syria; Men; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref55, 52, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; 12145; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Food; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Food; Syria; Gatherings; Parties
  - A multi-generational group gathered around a table with food (duplicate ref52, 54, 51, 50, 49, 47)., Circa 1940-1960; 12146; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 8.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Food; Syria; Children; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties
  - A man and a woman dancing amidst a crowd., Circa 1950-1970; 12147; Unknown; 17.7 x 12.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Women; Syria; Men; Photographic Prints; Dancing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Parties; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - A group portrait of three men and two women seated at a table., Circa 1950-1970; 12148; Photo Rapide, Grand Hotel Bloudan, Semerjdian Frères, [Syria]; 13.1 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Syria; Women; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hotels; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gatherings; Events/Occasions
  - An individual portrait of one of Marie Rose Krikorian's children., Circa 1950-1970; 12149; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 17.1 x 12.2 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Children; Boys; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Damascus, Syria; Individual Portraits
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian seated at the head of a table with two men including Jareh Krikorian and two of her sons., Circa 1950-1975; 12318; Unknown; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Women; Furnishings; Men; Photographic Prints; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Restaurants/bars; Boys; Children; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of three men and two women at a table including Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian., Circa 1950-1975; 12319; Unknown; 12.7 x 17.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Drinks/Beverages; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - Marie Rose Krikorian's son seated in between two other children on a pew., Circa 1950-1975; 12320; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 12.2 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Churches; Damascus, Syria; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Books; Religious Sites; Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gloves; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - An individual portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian's son dressed in a bow tie., Circa 1950-1975; 12321; Studio Elias Hichme, Bab Tuma, Damascus, [Syria]; 17.3 x 12.2 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Damascus, Syria; Boys; Children; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with a group of men and women at a table with Coca-Cola., Circa 1950-1975; 12322; Unknown; 12.7 x 17.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Drinks/Beverages; Women; Men; Syria; Cigarettes; English Writing; Restaurants/bars; Arabic Writing
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian with officials of the Lebanese government., Circa 1940-1965; 12323; Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]; 13.2 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Cigarettes; Women; Men; Lebanon; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Officials; Events/Occasions; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Fur Garments; Drinks/Beverages; Smoking; Cigarettes; Facial Hair
  - Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian seated at a table with two other men., Circa 1945-1965; 12324; Unknown; 12.9 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Food; Men; Women; Syria; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose and Jareh Krikorian with Mr. and Mrs. Ernesto Crespo., Circa 1945-1965; 12325; Studio Safar & Vartan, Fardosse Street, Damascus, [Syria]; 12.9 x 17.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Women; Damascus, Syria; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of Marie Rose Krikorian at a table., Circa 1945-1965; 12326; Studio Garbis, Damascus, [Syria]; 12.9 x 17.9 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Food; Damascus, Syria; Women; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Gatherings; Group Portraits
  - A group portrait of Mr. and Mrs. Krikorian with two men., Circa 1945-1965; 12327; A. Issa & Hadaya, Bab-Edriss, Beirut, [Lebanon]; 12.5 x 17.6 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Lebanon; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Fur Garments; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Smoking; Cigarettes
  - Marie Rose Krikorian with a group of men and women at a table., Circa 1945-1965; 12328; Antoine Dalati & Nohra, Official Photographer of the Lebanese Government, Ghrawi, Assour, [Lebanon]; 13.2 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Furnishings; Lebanon; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
  - Marie Rose Krikorian and a woman eating in a buffet line., Circa 1945-1965; 12329; 11.9 x 17.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)